Alexander Dymo

http://www.alexdymo.com | http://www.linkedin.com/in/adymoalex@alexdymo.com | 312-709-3026 | Chicago, IL

Objective

Startup software executive looking to apply his skills as the VP of Engineering at a larger, faster growing company.

Summary

Director of Engineering with 8.5 years of experience building and running small development teams in both product and service business. Co-founder of Y Combinator-backed online project management startup Acunote. Free and open source software developer. Programmer at heart.

Strengths

Realistic strategic planning

Stems from 7 years of building the project management software product, 5 years of project management research, and 8 years of experience in creating and executing 6 month to 3 year long roadmaps.

Evaluating and hiring software developers

Result of continuous application and refinement of the interview process developed while serving as the Director of Engineering. This process finds the 2% of candidates that fit and ensures 90% of them become the successful employees.

Managing entropy

Proven track record of decreasing entropy. For example, changed the development team culture that allowed 20% complete hacks into the one that produces 80% complete working solutions, managed the successful 2-year transition from service oriented to monolith architecture to increase stability and development speed with the inexperienced team, lead the refactoring of the large software project architecture with more than 200k lines of C++ code into the foundation that is still used 10 years after its completion.

Written communication

Side-effect of being a published technical writer. Documented processes, architecture, compliance requirements, implementation statuses, and more. Wrote developer onboarding guides, culture, and values descriptions. Maintained status dashboards for the executive team.

Making things happen across department and organization boundaries

Result of 3.5 years of working in the electricity retail business where dual reporting is a norm and any solution requires input from various departments within the company and from external entities like public utilities and state regulators.

Experience

Eligo Energy

Chicago, IL

Director of Engineering acting as VP of Engineering

Aug 2013 – present

- Managed engineering department at Eligo Energy, retail energy supplier that operates in 11 states. Reported directly to President (there is no VP level of management in the company organization chart).
- Built software that sales department and outside partners and brokers use to sell energy to residential and commercial customers and enroll them with the public utility. Deployed CRM and billing systems. Grew and trained the development team. Technologies used: .NET, MS SQL Server, Azure, Ruby on Rails, ReactJS, PostgreSQL, Heroku, AWS S3.
- Developed technology allows the company to make \$5M in monthly sales with less than 15 people doing sales and managing partner relations.

Acunote

Director of Engineering

Foster City, CA Jun 2008 – Jun 2013

• Directed the development of Acunote, the online project management and Scrum software used by IBM, EMC, HP, Fujitsu, FCC, USGS, and many startups. Reported directly to CEO.

- Built and managed the 100% remote team of engineers and designers working on a product.
- Was responsible for strategic planning, day-to-day execution, and product management. Also worked on advertizing and promotional campaigns.
- Attended Y Combinator in 2011 after they invested into the company.

Acunote

Foster City, CA

Founding Engineer

Jun 2006 – Jun 2008

- Developed the first release of the product single-handedly. Configured and automated deployment infrastructure. Worked on performance optimization.
- Released the first MVP in less than a month. Continued to build a product that attracted its first paying customer in less than a year and later generated \$500k in annual recurring revenue.
- Got a significant stock option grant, elevated to the co-founder status, and promoted to the position of Director of Engineering.

Ki-Inform

Mykolayiv, Ukraine

Co-founder and CTO

Jan 2005 – Apr 2006

• Co-founded Ki-Inform, the software consulting and business process optimization company. Was responsible for all types of software consulting work. Hired two employees, developed small business automation software, installed and integrated application servers.

Technical Writing Experience

Pragmatic Bookshelf

Author

May 2014 - present

• Wrote the Ruby Performance Optimization book published by Pragmatic Bookshelf in 2015 (https://ruby-performance-book.com).

Free Software Development Experience

KDE, KDevelop

Mykolayiv, Ukraine

Free Software Developer, Project Maintainer

2002 - 2012

- Member of the KDevelop team building the integrated development environment for Linux and other Unix systems that supports multiple programming languages.
- Designed and implemented the core architecture behind 4.x and 5.x versions of the product. Developed the user interface. Worked on C++ and Ruby language support plugins.
- Acted as a project maintainer and the release coordinator from 2003 to 2008. Was responsible for product and strategy decisions. Mentored new team members.

Academia Experience

National University of Shipbuilding

Mykolayiv, Ukraine

Associate Professor

2002 - 2013

• Taught Computational Linguistics and Artificial Intelligence courses for Linguistics majors.

Education

National University of Shipbuilding

Mykolayiv, Ukraine

PhD in Project Management (Operations Management)

1996 - 2007

PhD Dissertation (2007): Enhancement of open source software project management efficiency PE in Computer Science (2002)

MS in Energetics (2002)

BS in Energetics (2000)